hamidashita kaze wo atsumete mitai na
I want to try and gather the unrestrained winds
nami no saki tsutatte kanata e kaketeku
I'll run toward the horizon alongside the wave crests
kakugo wa kimatteru
I've made my decision
michi wa tookutemo
even if there's a long way to go on that road
egaita mirai e tsudzuiteru
I'll continue towards the future I've planned
toki ga bokura wo sekashite kodou ga supiido agetetta
time rushes us, the heartbeat speeds up
yume no naka de mezametemo onaji hikari wo sagashita
when I woke in the middle of a dream, I kept searching for that same light
kagayaku hoshizora no shita kazoekirenai seiza to kage
under the shining star-lit sky, with countless constellations and shadows
sono saki ni kimi wa nani wo nani wo mitsumete iru darou
there was something beyond that, what were you gazing at?
nani wo mitsumete iru darou
what were you gazing at?
{Run!!!
{The Curry of Life
Why do you go that far?
I'll get so strong that Guy-sensei
can look at me with a smile.
That is my Way of Ninja!
I see. So, you live for the sake
of Guy or whatever.
Then have that Guy person
give you a funeral!
I'm sure he'll think of your hard work
and cry for you!
Ninja Art...
Thunder Dragon Tornado!
One, two!
Mom, don't push!
I can't run that fast!
Oh, my, this isn't the time
for complaining!
Please, hurry!
I'll go on ahead, okay?
Oh, my!
Where'd he disappear to?
Has he evaporated to the bone?
Hey! Hang in there!
One, two!
I've had it.
Grandma Sansho, the curry of life!
One...
two!
I'll look after Lee.
So give Neji and Naruto
some curry!
Ranmaru, wait here.
Right.
I'm going to Naruto.
Please look after Lee.
You too. Get your butt to Neji!
Right, Mom.
Right. Open Lee's mouth.
Oh, right.
Here!
So even the curry of life
won't work, huh?
Oh, my.
You little...! This isn't the time
to be passing out!
Hot!
What are you doing?
Are you awake?
Oh, Tenten?
Didn't you fall off the cliff?
You should've realized
that was his trap.
What? I was totally snow-jobbed!
Neji, Neji!
It's the curry of life!
Eat this and get better.
Neji?
Neji!
Oh, my, thank goodness he got better!
What?
The world is spinning.
He's acting kind of strange.
Oh, my.
One, two...
Put the curry of life in this,
pot and all.
Okay.
Hot!
The curry.
This is bad!
Don't worry about it. Move it!
On account of that wine...
Will he be okay?
Oh, my, there's a slight problem
with the ingredients.
But there shouldn't be
much difference in efficacy.
But...
Oh, my.
He's coming this way.
It's okay. I'll go.
You're still alive?
I have to finish you off.
Raiga.
You're alive, Ranmaru?
It's Ranmaru!
That kid gave Raiga his own Chakra
and brought him back to life.
What?
Raiga looked at Ranmaru,
who was unconscious,
and assumed he was dead.
So, that's why he was saying
all that gibberish
about Ranmaru watching
from high above.
And I managed to get Ranmaru
to the Curry of Life Shop.
So, that's what happened.
We'll again be together forever,
Ranmaru.
Let's kill them and have fun
doing lots of bad things.
Right, Raiga.
Some fog has appeared.
It's okay.
I'll be your eyes again, Raiga.
Right. There's nothing to be afraid of
if I'm with you, Ranmaru.
Now, let's go, Raiga.
What about them?
They're dead now.
Right. Shall we search
for our next prey?
But there's a precipitous cliff ahead.
That Ranmaru, what's he going to do?
Could it be...
he's going to atone for the past sins
together with Raiga?
He might be planning to lead Raiga
over that cliff and die together.
What?
What's with you, jerk?
Lee.
Hey.
Here I go!
What?
You... brat!
He suddenly recovered!
Knock it off!
He's fast!
You okay, Ranmaru?
You stay here.
Take me with you.
Ranmaru.
Where'd you go, Ranmaru?
You little...!
You're going to pay for this!
Ninja Art... Thunder Armor!
Now...
Bring it!
Knock it off!
Here I go.
That was a heck of a blow.
If I hadn't put on the Thunder Armor,
I'd be giving myself a funeral.
In order to remember your hard work,
I'll give you your funeral myself!
Wait!
What's the idea?
I want to feed you
the curry of life, too.
You'll realize that you're not alone
if you eat the curry.
Everyone's feelings are blended in.
What are you saying?
Let's stop hurting people.
Cut it out!
You're my eyes and ears.
We'll no longer be two people in one
if you say such selfish things!
Shoot your lightning.
If I die, the strong Raiga will also die.
We're two in one, so...
I... won't be able to remember you
from when you were cool.
I must give you a funeral!
Stop, Raiga!
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
There are lots of Narutos.
Did I get drunk?
You little...! It makes no difference,
no matter how many of you there are!
Neji, wake up!
What are you doing, Neji?
Eat this and get it together.
We've got trouble here.
That's...
What?
Now we've done it.
You're going to kill by your own hand
the friend who risked his life
to save you?
Wha...? Ranmaru betrayed me.
He broke the promise for it
to be just us two forever.
He's not all alone anymore.
He figured out that it's more fun
to laugh with everyone
than to cry with you.
Naruto.
Ranmaru, you were going to die
with Raiga, weren't you?
Don't be thinking about
something like that anymore.
You're free now.
Don't worry. I won't let Raiga
give you a funeral, no matter what.
Hey, don't be shooting off your mouth,
you shrimp.
Say what?
Don't underestimate me.
I'm Raiga Kurosuki!
I've been counted before as one of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist.
I won't take orders from
the likes of you!
Oh, that's right.
He's a Ninja Swordsman, huh?
If you're one of the
Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist,
then I've got something to ask you.
You know the guy called Kisame, right?
Kisame? I hate that guy.
So, I'll give him a funeral for sure
the next time I see him.
What?
I hate him.
I hate all the Seven Ninja Swordmen
of the Mist.
Ranmaru, you're the only one
who's a friend to me.
But, Ranmaru,
you've made other friends.
We're not two in one anymore.
Raiga.
Impudent!
Who do you think taught you
about the outside world?
It's a funeral for you!
Clone Spinning Axe Kick!
You little...
Clone... Body Slam!
Ranmaru...
Now you're free.
Raiga?
Thunder! Give me my funeral!
One, two... One...
Not loud enough!
— You can't make genuine curry of life...
— One, two...
— if you don't stir it with all your heart!
Oh, my!
What are you doing, Mom?
Oh, my, Karashi!
It's a hundred years too soon for you
to be uttering the word "genuine"!
You too. Start your training over again
from the beginning!
What?
Grandma Sansho!
We'll be leaving now.
Thanks for your help.
I leave Ranmaru to you.
Oh, my. I'll train him mercilessly
as a successor
to the preparation of the curry of life.
Good luck, Ranmaru, Karashi.
— Thanks.
Oh, my. It's a long way
to the Village Hidden in Leaves.
I made you guys some special curry
that'll give you guys 10,000 times
the strength.
Be on your way after having some.
What's this very spicy-looking
bright red color?
It kind of hurts my eyes!
That looks good!
— What? Seriously?
CURRY OF LIFE
Tsunade-sama will get mad at us
if we don't get back soon.
You're right!
Unfortunately, we'll have to be going now.
Wait!
Oh, my, those kids were sure
bashful and reserved.
The curry. The curry!
dokomademo tsudzuku michi ni wa ironna koto arunda ne
so many things happen on this endless road, right?
tsuyogari na kimi ga kyou wa juwaki koshi ni namida koe
although you're strong-willed your voice wavered on the phone today
donna yume oikakete kokomade kitan darou
what dreams did you chase to get here?
wakara na kunattari suru koto wa boku ni datte aru kara nee BABY
even I have times when I just don't understand baby
kimi ga namida no toki ni wa boku ga soba ni iru kara
when you're sad I'll be close to you
hanareba nare no yoru datte boku wa soba ni iru kara
even on nights when we're apart I'll be close to you
boku wa soba ni iru kara
I'll be close to you
A captain's duty is to give prompt orders to his subordinates,
protect everyone and complete the mission quickly.
Woah! So cool!
This is just perfect for me, Lord Naruto, who will eventually become Hokage.
Alright! I'll get closer to becoming Hokage with this.
Next time:
"Everyone Comes With Me! A Takurami Survival of Sweat and Tears!"